In this video, we're going to look at how we can manipulate files in fast API.
So our goal is going to be to be able to send a file to our fast API, receive it on the backend and
perform some sort of operation, anything that we want to do with those particular files.
So basically, files are declared similarly to form fields.
They are in fact form fields and the system.
The browser will allow us to simply pass the URL of a file to our API and on the API side, we will
perform whatever manipulation we require.
So how do we do that?
Well, we simply declare the file as bytes, OK, and we set it as a default file.
This is actually quite important so that the system knows that we are trying to send a file as bytes
here.
Of course, if you know that you are receiving a string, you can convert those bytes to string or simply
use that as you require.
And then this particular object file is used to store files in memory.
OK, so we do have a limited space in memory, so that will be quite important.
This will be useful for small files, something that's not very big, only to be stored in memory.
So with that introduction, we're going to go into our code and see how we can implement this functionality
to send a file to our API.
Right.
So I am inside the router folder and I'm going to create a new file here, and I'm going to call it
File Dot P Y.
OK, now here I'm going to create a router, so from fast API import API router.
Then let's go ahead and declare our router as an API router, and we're going to provide here our prefix.
As for slash file and the tags as a list with one one entry, a file.
OK, so we have our file now.
Of course, we need to go into may not be why and added here, so I'm going to import it file and I'm
going to add it just somewhere below.
Authentication after that include writer and file dot router.
OK, so that's all for the main.
Now let's go ahead and create an endpoint.
We're going to hold this file and we're going to simply get the file that the user wants to send us.
OK, so router dot get.
Sorry, this is going to be a post because we need to send form elements here, so I'm going to say
forward slash file.
I'm going to define a function, get on the score file, and here I will receive a parameter file of
type bytes that is going to be, by default, a file, and we need to import that file here.
So from fast API import file.
All right.
So we have our function definition now, the implementation.
We're going to actually use this file as a string.
So we're going to assume that we get text in this file.
OK, so I'm going to say here content is going to be file dot decode.
So I'm going to decode these bytes that we receive as UTF Dash eight, UTF eight is going to be a simple,
plain text.
OK, now I have already created a file that will be used here, and it has a few different lines of
text, so I'm going to separate those and just print them out in the return object.
So I'm going to say Lines is going to be content dot split.
Over backslash.
OK, so that's going to split my content into different lines.
And then if I return.
I can return, for instance, lines as lines.
OK, so that should be all good if we send a small text file that will be split into its its lines and
then the lines will be returned in the object.
OK, so save that.
Go back to the documentation and refresh, and we have our new post method in that I'm going to try
it out.
You can see that it's multipart form data, so we need to select the file here, and I have a test file
that simply contains three lines of text.
If I execute that, that is being received out on the back and sides split into lines and I get the
output as a list.
OK, so I just get Helloworld.
Hi, how are you?
And this is a test file.
OK, so basically at this point, you can use these bytes for whatever your application your functionality
requires.
OK, so you can do anything you like with those bytes.
Now, keep in mind that, as I said, this is stored in memory, so the file must be quite small.
Otherwise the memory will fill up and you will get errors.
And also, this is quite limiting in what you can do.
You get simply a bunch of bytes and it's up to you to decide how to process those bytes.
Now, actually, Fast API provides us a better way to handle files.
This is just the most basic way for basic functionality, but we have other options and we will see
that option in the next video.